# **Ashutosh Kumar**

Experienced IT professional with over 8 years in the software industry, including 3 years specializing in DevOps. Currently serving as a Technical Consultant at Precisely, seeking a DevOps Engineer role to leverage extensive skills and drive innovation.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Precisely Software & Data India P. Limited - Technical Consultant Project - EnterWorks
July 2022 - PRESENT

- As a Technical Consultant, I manage global EnterWorks installations, ensuring seamless, successful deployments.
- Technologies used SQL Server, Installer, Windows OS

**Precisely Software & Data India P. Limited** - Software Engineer **Project** - Web Mapping Application May 2020 – June 2022

- I created InstallShield installers for a web mapping app, ensuring seamless installations. Managed CI/CD pipelines with TeamCity, reducing manual work by 70% and boosting efficiency.
- Managed Git Continuous Integration (CI) and configured custom runners using Docker.
- Set up a TeamCity project for Checkmarx scans.

**Technologies used**: TeamCity, GIT, PowerShell, Checkmarx, InstallShield, Docker, Windows & Linux OS

# Pitney Bowes Software India P. Limited - SDE Intern

**Project - Cross Border E-commerce** 

February 2016 – April 2020

- Automated software builds using Jenkins, configuring jobs, triggers, integrating with version control, and executing scripts.
- Managed development branches in version control for organizing features, bug fixes, and releases.
- Technologies worked on: Jenkins, SVN

#### **EDUCATION**

B. Tech in Computer Science and Engineering, Graduated in 2015 Uttar Pradesh Technical University, Lucknow

### **PROJECTS**

AWS Resource Usage Tracker using shell script

GitHub: AWS Resource Usage Tracker

Jenkins CI/CD pipeline for Java app GitHub: CI/CD Pipeline for Java App

Automated CI/CD Pipeline for Spring Boot Deployment with Jenkins & Docker

GitHub: Spring Boot CI/CD Pipeline

ADDRESS: Noida, Sector 66,

Uttar Pradesh Mobile: 9936514482

ashutoshkumar101094@gmail.co

m

www.linkedin.com/in/ashutosh-kumar-b0084212b

**TECHNICAL SKILLS** 

Cloud Computing: **AWS**CICD: **Jenkins, TeamCity**Containerization: **Docker**Scripting Languages: **Bash** 

VCS: **GIT, SVN**IaC Tool: **Terraform** 

Configuration Management:

Ansible

Application Server: **Apache** 

Tomcat

Familiar with **GitHub Actions** Operating Systems: **Windows**,

Linux

#### **AWARDS**

**R&R Award** for outstanding contributions to Cross Border E-commerce at Pitney Bowes.

Thumbs Up Award for outstanding performance on the Web Mapping Application project.

**Spot Award** from Precisely for exceptional performance on the EnterWorks project at Precisely

## **CERTIFICATES**

HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

### **LANGUAGES**

English, Hindi